Great Detective Conan
Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi"
Where...
...on earth am I?
Ran! Oi, Ran, wake up! Ran!
Shin'ichi?
Dad!
Sir...
Ah!
What happened? Where are we...
Shin'ichi, what's this about?
I haven't got a clue.
I can't remember anything.
And what is this all about?!
I told you, I don't know!
"Out of range"
Ah, my cell phone's out of range...
"Beloved Shin'ichi-sama, I'm your fan."
"I've been following your achievements."
"You're a wonderful detective."
"This white room is a present for you."
"Please enjoy yourself"
What is this...
Dunno.
However, the one thing that is for certain
is that someone is holding us prisoner.
Who?
And for what reason?
What's going to happen to us?
Say something, boy detective!
I told you, I'm thinking!
If I'm certain, this date is...
The one where I solved a murder case before.
Could it be...
That famous photographer who took his
wife's sister who was a model as his lover...
Yes.
It was that case...
I don't think this'll work.
I just can't betray my older sister anymore.
Momoko...
Tsubochi-san, you're my sister's husband.
It's time to end this.
You can take your camera back.
Don't tell me...
you've gotten another man?
Why? That couldn't be so.
It is so.
I told you I didn't, didn't I?
Shape up...
Don't mess with me!
Hello.
Ah, is that you Sensei?
I should be arriving at the
model Aida-san's apartment very soon.
Eh? Why?
What, have you forgotten?
We have a photo shoot session
with her at 4 pm.
That's right...
Ah, that's right.
"Komehana City Court"
"5 minutes later"
Yo.
Hello.
Aida-san! Are you in?
Ala? It's open.
What?
Who are you? Stop!
Thank you very much!
"High School Student Detective
Kudoć Shin'ichi"
How many hours have I waited while
you had your nails done? Has the sun set?
It's okay from time to time.
Sonoko went to a lot of trouble to
get me those free tickets, after all.
Point is, why do I have to be the one
who goes with you?
Because!
I can't use my hands to shop for dinner
right after having my nails done, can I!
So in the end, I'm just your bag carrier.
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend
Mori Ran"
If all you're gonna do is look at your nails...
...then you've looked
and we're done here now, right?
Geez!
You don't understand at all.
When seeing your reflection in the mirror,
what's important is how the whole balance looks.
Anyhow, I'm absolutely never
going out with you again.
Whaa!
What was that scream?
Are you okay?
Please hang in there!
Ah, it hurts...
What happened?
A robber...
There was a robber.
More importantly, there's Aida-kun!
Aida-san! Please hang in there!
Aida-san!
How's Aida-kun?
It's too late...
Aida-kun...
What is this?
Wake up, Aida-kun!
Aida-kun!
What happened?
"MPD Investigation Unit One
Sato Miwako"
Takagi Wataru"
That's why, because of your abundant
experience in love, I need your advice.
How would I check the room of a woman
who was living alone...
...to see whether or not
they had a boyfriend?
"Private Detective - Mori Kogoro"
What?
Boy detective, just where are you right now?
Never mind about that.
More importantly, give me some ideas about
whether a man has been living here or not.
The standard is if there's a toothbrush
or if the toilet seat is up, that's suspicious.
After that, look around for hobbies
a man would be into.
Even if she had just started being under
the influence of a boyfriend...
...there should be plenty of those.
Well, well, that would be my method,
...but I think such cases are rare and sad
when they do happen, aren't they?
Thank you.
If a woman is going out with a man that way,
they have plans about seeing each other, right?
The man would have to be especially careful,
and when it gets serious...
...it's really the man you see
crying in the end, it's really the man.
Hey, you hung up on me!
Ah!
She disappeared.
No, it's best if you don't come.
It'd be too big a shock.
It wouldn't be good for
the child inside you, either.
Anyhow, get in touch with
your mother and father...
I see. You were struck by a man
who suddenly ran away from inside.
Yes.
Right with the shock of being hit,
all I could see was a pure white.
It was incredibly powerful.
Kishi-san, what was the weapon
you were attacked with?
I don't know.
But, I think it was an iron pipe or something.
An iron pipe or something...
The time when you were knocked out...
"Cameraman's Assistant
Kishi Kousuke"
Um...
Ah, I'm late in introducing myself.
I'm Kudoć Shin'ichi.
I'm a student going to Teitan High School.
This is the high school detective,
Kudoć Shin'ichi-kun.
He's helping us out in
our investigation this time around.
Eh?! THAT great detective?
"Professional Cameraman
Tsubochi Yuuhei"
Is it as Kishi-san said?
Um...
I'm Tsubochi.
Aida-kun's brother-in-law.
When you say you're her brother-in-law...
Yes, she was my wife's younger sister.
The sisters were close.
Are these photos of Tsubochi-san
and your wife's wedding?
Yes.
Ehh...
These are terrific photos.
I long for wedding photos such as these.
Eh?
Ah...
Really?
I'm not interested in having any.
Eh? Eh? Ah, really? Is that right?
- More importantly, Detective.
- Yes?
Haven't you found the criminal yet?
Not that much time has passed since
he hit us and ran off, has there?
We're performing
an intensive search right now...
Please make sure to arrest him!
It was a man of large build
with a scar on his forehead.
He had cropped, black hair.
He was incredibly violent.
Cropped, black hair
and with a scar on his forehead...
Where have I hear that before...
Aren't those the features of Murozaki,
the suspect wanted for those serial robberies?
In that case, there's a wanted poster for
that criminal on the lower floor.
Eh? There was?
- Takagi-kun, go and get it.
- Yes. Understood.
I took a photo of it with my cell phone.
I see.
"Wanted Criminal
Murozaki Eiji"
How about it?
It's not something I can be
sure about in just an instant...
Still, I think he did resemble him.
I'll urgently arrange for his arrest!
He's a wanted criminal! Those arrangements
would have been made long ago.
What sort of personality
did your sister-in-law have?
She was cheerful and sociable...
...the type with lots of friends.
She had been living abroad for a long time.
After she returned to Japan,
she was actively working for fashion magazines.
She also helped me
in my job by being my model...
She was a very beautiful
and excellent woman.
Was there anyone
who bore a grudge against her?
No way!
Um...
The criminal was a robber, wasn't it?
Why would you ask something like that?
Truth is, I think it was someone
other than a robber.
Eh?
As Tsubochi-san noticed as well...
...Aida Momoko-san had choke marks
on her neck where she was strangled by hand.
However, you two were struck by...
...an iron pipe of some sort that
the criminal had brought with him.
In that case, Aida-san should have been
attacked with that pipe as well.
Yet why would the criminal
kill someone by strangling them?
It's strange they didn't use
that weapon, isn't it?
How is it?
There's no doubt she was strangled
and it was death by suffocation.
Moreover, her personal items were scattered about
and there were traces of pollen left behind.
Pollen?
Ah, from those flowers.
Those are Casablancas.
Do you know what they mean
in flower language?
Isn't it... "dignity"?
That has nothing to do with this case...
does it.
I guess it was a robbery after all, wasn't it?
Since he mentioned a scar on the forehead,
I think it's immediately obvious.
Yeah. Wouldn't it have been Murozaki?
But Detective Takagi, take a closer look.
This is the method done by an amateur.
For a professional robbery crime,
to me this is a little...
Yeah. But, but...
A strange man did pop out
from inside here and ran off.
The both of them witnessed him.
That's true, isn't it?
"Just what is the true character
of this stranger..."
"...that both Kishi-san
and Tsubochi-san encountered?"
I'm going back home for now.
I'm worried about my pregnant wife.
She suddenly lost her sister like this.
I wonder how big a shock she's had.
Please wait!
Something else?
Once I've looked in on my wife,
I'll talk to the police again.
Some reason I can't?
Well, it's nothing all that big...
...but there is something
I was a little curious about...
When the two of you arrived here,
the front door was open, wasn't it?
Yes.
Why would it have been unlocked?
Normally if a thief is simply
ransacking a place...
...they'd lock the door out of fear.
We just happened to see him at the
same time he was coming out, didn't we?
At the exact same moment
Tsubochi-san and Kishi-san appeared?
Unfortunately, our timing was bad.
Kudoć-kun, what's been
bothering you since earlier?
Truth is, I've been thinking
the same thing over and over.
"Was this really a robbery?"
Eh?
A ransacking like this
is the work of an amateur.
I can't help but think
this case is more like...
...a murder that's been covered up
to look like the act of a thief.
Which is it?
We were both attacked by
the criminal, weren't we?
It was that guy who wrecked this place.
There's no mistake about that.
A heavy-built man with a scar
on his forehead. With cropped, black hair.
That's right. I know that.
You may be a famous great detective,
but you're still just a high school student.
I want a proper police investigation.
Detective Takagi, Detective Sato,
I'll be counting on you.
Well then, please excuse me for now.
Just one more thing.
What is it?
What is this?
It's a pretty big thing.
That's a strobe lamp.
What would such a large strobe lamp
be doing in a model's home?
This is mine.
She said she wasn't just interested in being
photographed but in how photos are taken, too...
...so I loaned it to her.
Ehh...
By the way, this strobe lamp...
...is still a little warm.
I wonder if Aida-san was using it?
She said she wanted to study camera work.
So there's the possibility she may have.
This is enough, isn't it?
Well then, excuse me.
No, this is strange.
What is it this time?!
There's something not in this apartment
that should be here.
What's that?
A camera.
Huh?
Aida-san was interested in taking photos.
She even had a darkroom to process them.
This strobe lamp is still warm.
Nevertheless, the essential camera...
...isn't here.
Don't you find that strange?
It may have been
one of the things that was stolen.
So long, excuse me.
Ah! What a gorgeous full-length mirror!
I hope I can get such a big one for my home.
What are you doing?
Huh? Ala?
It's turned in a strange direction.
It only reflects half of me.
I see!
That's how it was!
Ran, thank you.
Eh? For what?
Have you discovered something, Kudoć-kun?
I've seen it.
The one and only truth.
Actually, why would this strobe lamp
still be warm after all this time?
And then earlier,
Ran found the answer to that for me.
What would that be, Kudoć-kun?
It's this full-length mirror at the front door.
It only shows half your body.
It's angle has been twisted.
Excuse me a moment.
Hmm?
I'm not sure I get it...
The trick was to show the both of them
that there was a criminal...
...when one didn't exist.
First off, the criminal set up
this large strobe lamp...
...in a place where it would be
in a blind spot from the door.
And then...
...he adjusted this full-length mirror...
...to be set at an angle.
The rest was just a game of timing.
The moment Kishi-san opened the door...
...the criminal turned on this switch.
And then what happened?
The intense flash of light directly struck
Kishi-san's eyes, blinding him.
Huh? Hang on a sec.
In that case, wouldn't the criminal
have been in this room after all?
If he hadn't been, he wouldn't have been
able to press this switch, would he?
No, this strobe lamp
can be controlled remotely.
It's part of the technology
any pro cameraman would have.
And this flash belongs to
the cameraman, Tsubochi-san.
When the electronic flash function of his
camera is turned on and the shutter released...
...this strobe lamp catches the infrared signal
from it and causes a flash.
Tsubochi-san...
...could you press the shutter on the digital
SLR camera you have around your neck?
Tsubochi-san, if you would please.
Ah! That's that had incredible power!
At this moment,
I can't tell what's going on.
And then, at the same moment of the flash...
...the criminal took his weapon
and hit Kishi-san over the head with it.
Since there was a difference in heights...
...a breeze would have come from
the effect of the impact.
Kishi-san wouldn't have known
what had hit him.
By the way...
...the weapon was probably a tripod.
A pro cameraman carries one
around with him wherever he goes.
Hold on there, you.
Then are you saying...
Yes.
The criminal who killed Aida Momoko-san...
...was you, Tsubochi-san.
How dare you come up with such crap.
And I heard you were a great detective.
Are you denying it?
Yeah.
All of your nonsense.
This trick you so proudly announced...
...is just one of many possibilities
you could have pointed out.
But...
...in order to treat someone as a criminal...
...it's essential you have evidence.
Weren't you and Aida-san seeing one another?
Your wife's younger sister.
That would have been an excellent motive.
Don't mess with me!
I'm telling you to show me some evidence.
Besides, there's no way I'd betray my wife!
You're awfully eager to get away
from this crime scene.
Isn't that because you want the chance
to conceal some evidence?
Don't joke around.
That's nothing but speculation.
In that case...
...you won't mind if we ask
for your camera bag.
Despite having a camera
hanging off your shoulder...
...why are you clinging to
that bag so tightly?
That's just stupid.
A pro cameraman always carries around
not only his camera but another one as backup.
It's just that simple!
Isn't this a film camera?
What's more, it's also a classic camera.
Since you normally work
using a digital camera...
...why would you have
a film camera as backup?
Something wrong with that?
Tsubochi-san.
I regret this,
but you shouldn't pass along lies.
What?
This is my reasoning.
This camera...
...is the true camera that should be
in Aida-san's apartment.
Anyhow, after you had killed Aida-san...
...you noticed the presence of
this camera and took it with you.
Doesn't this camera contain a photo...
...showing evidence of your crime?
That's stupid.
In that case, you won't mind
if we have this camera investigated.
If...
...something related to a crime
isn't in there at all...
...just what would you do?
At that time...
...I would completely give up
being a detective.
Shin'ichi, are you sure about this?
Yeah.
All right.
Take it.
Well then, the truth.
The photos left in this camera
will give us the answer to that, won't they?
- If you would please.
- Yes.
"It's okay."
"There's nothing in that camera about either me
or Momoko from the time of the crime."
"There's no possibility at all
that anything will come out of it."
Just a little longer.
I can see it.
How about it?
Now you understand, don't you?
I wasn't me who killed her.
It was that thief!
Kudoć-kun! They're identical.
It's the same pollen.
99% probability.
Pollen?
From the camera.
Pollen from the Casablancas at the crime site
were detected on the body of this camera.
By the way, these flowers came to Aida-san
through a local florist this morning.
It was discovered during the investigation
that that's when she bought them.
Why would pollen from these flowers...
...be clinging to your camera when...
...you hadn't even been in
her apartment yet today?
Tsubochi-san...
...right after you murdered Aida-san...
...you touched this camera
with your hands, didn't you?
Lies...
I heard that the pollen was detected...
...throughout the room and on
all the things scattered around.
If you had taken that camera
out of this apartment...
...it's certain pollen would
have been stuck to it, too.
And...
...even if you knew pollen was going around...
...you would still have insisted on always
carrying that camera with you, wouldn't you?
Most likely...
...that camera symbolized
the close relationship you had with Aida-san.
The camera...
Momoko's camera...
To be honest...
...I wasn't really interested in the pictures
contained in that camera.
I just wanted to buy some time to have
the pollen that was stuck to it checked out.
Since you couldn't be arrested
without some physical evidence...
...and since it also clarified
some of your tricks at the same time.
You're wrong.
I didn't do anything bad.
This woman...
This woman was toying with me...
That's why I had to do it!
You...
Even so, you're a professional cameraman.
These photos...
Take a good look at the
final photographs that Aida-san took.
I... love... you.
"I love you."
That's what she was saying.
We received a report from
the coroner a moment ago.
They said that after she was strangled,
she lived for quite a while afterwards.
Tsubochi-san.
If you hadn't wasted time trying to cover up your
actions and had called an ambulance immediately...
...she might have been saved.
I'm certain she wanted to protect...
...both her sister and the man that she loved.
Aida-san...
...was trying to suppress the feelings
she had for you...
...and so chose to break up with you.
Such a brave and pure woman...
The woman who loved you
from the bottom of her heart...
With your hand...
...you've buried her in the earth!
Momoko...
I'm so sorry.
Momoko!
I feel so sorry for Aida-san.
Momoko...
"I Love You"
"What is this!
Just who is doing this and why?"
"What're we gonna do?
Hey, Shin'ichi!"
"I told you, I'm thinking about it!"
"YOU DON'T HAVE TO SHOUT!"
"That day...
That was the day of the case where
I confronted that psychic..."
It's said she was killed psychically.
If I recall, that case...
"After this
A New Challenge For Shin'ichi"
"Murdered by Psychic Ability?!"
"This drama is fictional"